[Music]
hello everyone and welcome to react
native you 2019 so I'm really excited to
have you all here today and let me tell
you why I've been excited for past few
months so react native is doing great
and this is the reason why I'm so
excited to have you all here for the
next two days to talk about it
we're having more contributions that
we've ever had we are merging more PRS
every day we are shipping more features
our conference has almost twice as many
oddities as last year so we are growing
as well yeah life is good so you know if
there is anybody here in the audience
that doesn't share this enthusiasm with
me don't worry we got two days filled
with talks to get you excited about that
so let me open it up and tell you some
details and explain you why I've been so
crazy about react native recently nine
months ago we asked the community what
do you dislike about react native which
gave us a good overview of the problems
you are facing and to do so we have used
the react Native community a github
organization we have set up on our way
to increase the transparency and move
the discussions about the react native
and its future into public space rather
than happening on Twitter and closed
circles on this card and there has been
a lot of comments and meaningful
feedback about react native that we have
grouped into several categories the
first one is the developer experience
everything related to working and
building react native apps the other
category is community support so
transparent and predictable development
path and better support from the core
team at Facebook and the last one is
performance so making sure that not only
we can shift respect from apps but also
we can make them fast so let's go one by
one starting from the top one the
developer experience so based on your
feedback and what the community is
struggling with there is free areas that
are getting popular that are getting
particular attention from you that is
upgrading react native apps and making
sure that it's easy to do or at least
that you know what's kind of steps you
should perform yourself another one is
debugging so being able to test your app
while it's running be able to develop
faster these are the promises of react
native that should work out of the box
and the last one is the documentation
which is extremely valuable to bring in
new developers to react native but we
are also using it every day to look up
the API to look up the props or read
some guides so this is for sure
something that we should pay extreme
attention to so let's start with
upgrading upgrading is personally hard
because while making react native apps
we are dealing with multiple build
systems not only we have to build Java
Script which already has hundreds of
ways when you are doing web development
but also you have to deal with iOS
development Android development which
are totally different worlds and
different infrastructures so we've been
working on minimizing the surface that
you are working with so that we can
perform more changes ourselves behind
the scenes including breaking changes
and we have worked on this one really
hard
first the contributors there are members
of react Native community have worked
really hard on a tool called upgrade
helper for immediate improvements while
we work on the other areas as well and
so the upgrade helper tool aims to
provide you yeah
[Applause]
so the upgrade helper tool Ellis to give
you a full set of changes that happen
between any two versions so this will
help you to see what you exactly need to
change yourself and aside from that this
tool has a couple of extra handy
features such as inline comments to help
you have more insights as to what
particle of fires are doing so that if
you haven't looked into your Gradle
files you can now figure out by the way
this is what this file is doing which is
really handy and there's much more than
that so I strongly recommend you look at
it check out the repo stir it and check
all the features they have prepared for
you so that's the first thing better up
great journey with new tools and another
one that I'm also excited about is the
outer linking so no more react native
link which makes your native
dependencies work automatically all you
have to do is to run the installation of
your node package manager and then the
dependencies are ready for you to use
and this feature heavily relies on
khakha ports on iOS and Gradle obviously
on Android and that means it is now
preferred and default way of handling
third-party native dependencies and
we're not done yet we'll continue making
the upgrade process even better there is
a a bunch of helpful ideas there
floating around react native community
so if you have any ideas or comments
regarding these just make sure to go to
react native community discussion and
proposals repo where you can check
issues and give your impact as to what
we should be doing another area of focus
is debugging and that's the section I'm
excited the most because it includes
features that we are yet about to ship
so first thing is thanks to Hermes we
can finally experiment with on-device
debugging so what that means is that
when you start debugging your code the
code will remain running on your device
instead of running in a Chrome browser
so that gives you this ability to
reproduce bags with more confidence
since you are using the same engine as
your users are using and I'll mention
Hermes
later in this section and we will hear
about it quite a lot with the next two
days so another great feature that maybe
many of you haven't heard about yet that
is about to ship is integration with
flipper
and the flipper is what we've been all
waiting for this is what everybody was
mentioning is a disadvantage of using
react native that there was no debugging
platform or a way to debug react native
app and you had to use a bunch of other
tools to do it
one for iOS one for Android one for
JavaScript flipper is a brand new
platform for debugging mobile apps it
lets you inspect the layout of your
react native apps look up contents of
icing storage as you work with it or
even use react dev tools they're
integrated right away no Easter work is
needed and what's great is that it's not
tied to any particular platform so as I
said you can already use it in Android
and iOS as well so if you are developing
brownfield or a native apps from time to
time as well you can use the same tool
and don't learn new tool all over
so that's shipping with next react
native version watch out for updates and
the last feature that I wanted to cover
which is as exciting as flipper support
is fast refresh so fast refresh is the
new hot module reloading that works is
fast and predictable and just to give
you an idea how much the team is
confident that it's stable it is turned
on by default yes so when I was when I
was testing it I I was like how do I
turn this thing on and then I realized
wow it's already working and that's
that's that's you know that's those tiny
little things that you'd expect from
react native and it's already available
in the current RC channel it's ready for
you to try today so just make sure you
install the latest which is 61 RC 2
right now and let us know and on top of
that we've been also working really hard
on making our documentation and
marketing much better in fact you know
there's there is now a dedicated
personal Facebook to constantly
challenged our dogs and her name is
Rachel and she's here with us today so
if you have any ideas how to make our
documentation better just look for
Rachel and please have a chat and this
area is still in development so I'm
gonna give you an idea what we have been
working on what the team is up to so as
I said the Decatur team
and as a result of what we've been
working on in the past months the team
has chipped a entirely new react native
screen as well as redesigned them home
page of react native website to give it
more to emphasize more on the react
native features and make it more
exciting for developers that are looking
to understand why is it really react
needed I should try but we are now
particularly looking into API Docs
making sure that the documentation
reflects the current state of props as
well as providing you with more guides
to help you build the react native apps
not necessarily guides that only relate
to the components and ApS that are part
of react native but also something
broader in the future is something we
are considering as well so that's it
about developer experience let's move on
to the another section which is
community support and for improving the
community support and stability of the
framework we have worked together with
Facebook on investing more time into
open source and prioritizing community
contributions and in the community so as
a part of that we have put a lot of
effort into lean core and try to move
faster of the peers so starting with the
linker this is a codename for a process
that we have started a while back ago to
reduce the surface of react native to
make it smaller and allow the community
to take better care of modules that were
not necessarily needed for core
functionalities and that were not
necessarily used in certainly at
Facebook so there was no reason to tie
these modules into the Facebook
infrastructure and by extracting that
code into react Native community org
we were able to get much more people
involved into the project these modules
are now my team by a healthier and more
diverse communities showing that this is
a great step for the community where we
have notices that by giving developers
and community ownership and
responsibility their development of
these libraries accelerates to the level
that we haven't seen before a great
example is webview that in a first month
of being a separate project merged over
a hundred of peers adding features and
functionalities people have wanted for
long and this is significantly more than
we were ever able before in the history
of the webview and other modules as well
in total we have merged over
800 PRS combined to the extracted
projects including webview a sink
storage net info website of course the
CLI we are really excited to see other
pieces of react may be following the
same in a future and improving their
quality significantly so history Klee
speaking we have sort of deprioritized
community contributions and as a result
of that we have accumulated almost 300
pool requests in last December and
that's quite a lot and we've been
working on reducing that number to
around 50 and simultaneously the average
number of pull requests that people were
selling increased from 3.5 per day to 7
so in other words we have merged almost
600 pairs in past six months I think
that's that's really impressive that's
more almost 75 of all peers ever
submitted in that amount of time and if
I I took a look historically at the
ratio between merged and sent PRS and we
are actually increasing that so I'm
hoping to make that number even higher
and the result is noticeable immediately
with react native being the second most
contributed project on github with over
10,000 contributors of any kind and
2,000 contributors that contributed code
thanks to that we are moving faster and
is a healthy thing so I think the
takeaway from this section is that if
you have ever sent a PR in the past and
you burnout because we haven't murdered
in two years give it a try again
so aside from making all these great
contributions that we have packed into
more than 42 releases including major
and minor versions I want to call out
Microsoft and all the great tools
they've been making for react native
recently so obviously from Cote push up
Center and react native windows they've
been always extremely focused on
building enterprise ready tooling around
react native but now they are finally
connecting the dots and starting to use
react native not only in Skype and
products similar but also in their
flagship products including office suit
which makes me really excited this is an
indicator that react native is
enterprise ready and this is
impression that I'm also getting from
our clients of coal stock as well and
that's really amazing because we're real
native shines is the brownfield
integrations integrations with existing
native apps which is essentially what
Enterprise is all about and I'm really
looking forward to Ryan's talk on Friday
morning where we're gonna have some
deals about Bradfield integrations as
well as the Microsoft Talk
where they gonna sure how do they really
use react native and once they're yet to
come so pretty excited about that so
last thing I'd like to mention here is
the performance something that I hear
almost all the time I go start pitching
react native especially to native
developers everybody's like oh you got
this async bridge thank you Rufus react
native has already acceptable
performance out of the box and I'm
saying this because when I was doing
native apps myself I did a lot of hacky
code which ended up blocking main thread
on iOS and so it's not that easy to
build a fast up on iOS but with react
native you get certain level of
performance out of the box but that's
not enough for us and we'll hear a lot
about this moving next two days but
there's just two areas that I wanted to
highlight in this section one of them
being Hermes and the other one being
Metro so starting from Hermes that's
been released a chain react another
react native conference that you should
save your calendar if you are especially
coming from States and it's a JavaScript
engine that features ahead of time
static compile optimizations and compact
byte code size and unlike traditional
JavaScript engines Hermes is optimized
specifically for running react native on
mobile devices and it's not meant to be
used on the web so when I asked Facebook
team why did you really start
investigating things like Hermes what
they told me is that traditional
JavaScript engines are usually optimized
for 10 maybe 20 most impactful websites
on the Internet and this is not how
react native works and so this is
actually true and the reason they and
you can actually see the benefits of
that approach almost immediately because
as soon as they released it and that's
like very first version we get the
improvements right away for example the
time to interaction is improved by two
seconds just like that and the
application size gets by 90 megabytes
smaller
this is not the end this is the just the
beginning of improvements that we are
yet to see and I think this is an
example there's an amazing example
showing that Facebook treats react
native seriously there's been a lot of
people asking whether Facebook was
really committed to react native things
like Hermes don't happen every day I
don't remember seeing a JavaScript
engine being created since I'm into
development which is maybe like 10 years
and only now I think this is great
because what we are getting is high
speed optimized engine for our use cases
and now we can finally move especially
Android side to the next level of
performance so parsing and executing
JavaScript battle is one thing but
generating the code in a performant way
is another thing and that's what the
team of Metro's had been working on for
the past few months so amongst many
features they've shipped because since
the extraction of packager to a separate
project Khanna the first linker project
they started shipping a lot a lot of
features and I wanted to highlight a
feature called inline requires the let's
metro identify components that can be
lazy loaded and as a result modules are
required with a delay as soon as they
are needed for us to use this is
different to requiring everything at the
same time and can be specifically useful
if your app is big and contains a lot of
modules together with Hermes this is a
nice combination to improve your
performance and lazy load parts of your
bundle and if you haven't used it yet
and working on a bigger app you can give
it a try and let us know how it works
for you so that was a brief look at the
all the improvements we have shipped in
the recent months and will continue to
align with the community every once in a
while to make sure that the direction we
have picked is still aligned with the
expectations of the community in fact we
just started another edition of the
survey in order to check the status of
react native once again and see if any
of these improvements had real impact on
you looking forward to learning more
about that please check discussions and
proposals and let us know what you think
and also I'd like to thank Christophe
who's not here with us today he's also
working at Facebook who's been doing all
these great initiatives trying to gather
feedback and then do a lot of moderation
work Christophe thank you for that this
is really great work
Kaka I can I wanted he will do the
keynote but he could very important
things so maybe next year Christopher
alright so I think there is a bright
future ahead in front of react native
with the vibrant community that you are
part of Facebook commitment and support
from other partners I think we are on
the right track and at this pace
reducing the number of issues to a bare
minimum and improving the quality of the
framework I think it's just a matter of
time don't quote me on that but I think
that most of the issues that we know
today will soon be fing away past in
fact some of them are already under
heavy development and this is what this
conference is all about getting you up
to date and getting you know the
community around you and around react
native and speaking of the community I
are open source and react Native
community a lot working with people
across the world gave me the opportunity
to overcome environmental barriers that
I was facing living in a very small city
somewhere in the countryside of Poland
and you know thanks to open source and
all the great people that I've met I was
not only able to become a bird Avella
per but I was also able to set up coal
stack and continue spreading the
enthusiasm with people around me and now
I feel privileged to be standing in
front of you and all I want to say is
that my goal is to give you all the same
opportunity starting today so without
making it any longer
thank you for making it to the react
native EU 2019 and I wish you have a
great conference so let's make it
officially start
so before we continue to our first
speaker I wanted to thank our sponsors
that helped us make this conference
happen they are with us every year and
if they wasn't for for them we would
probably have a hard time getting things
set up so please give them a huge round
of applause
[Applause]